# SAHILKUMAR AHIR

8/663-664 Bharvad Faliya, Navsari Bazar, Opp. Sagrampura Police Station, Surat-395002 +919714458666

Sahilahir333@gmail.com

Computer Engineer and Content Writer, with a little professional experience as an intern in both the fields, and a curious being. Driven and self-motivated have managed two projects during my bachelor's as a team leader, which justifies my leadership and communication skills. With a positive attitude, hardworking skills, and proper guidance, I will be the absolute best of myself. Other than that, very passionate about football.

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### **JUNE 2019 – JANUARY 2020**

## INTERN(WEB DEVELOPER - ANGULAR), KNOXPO

I hold an internship at a reputed software solution company called KNOXPO. There we did a project based on Angular, Firebase, and Android Studio. The project was to establish a digital platform between the motor driving school and its customers. We have completed our final year project under their guidance and have learned various technical and non-technical skills.

#### **DECEMBER 2020 – FEBURARY 2021**

# INTERN(CONTENT WRITER, BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT MANAGER), MD TECH CONSULTANCY SERVICES

I was selected as a Technical Content Writer for a tech company. My role was to write Technical content as per their requirements. The other responsibility was to write compiling theme contents and articles around various themes/topics. Later they offered me a business development manager position, and I agreed to it. I have worked as a content writer and business development manager.

#### **APRIL 2021 - JULY 2021**

#### **INTERN(WEB DEVELOPER – CORE PHP),** TRADINGET

I was hired as an intern at Tradinget. It is one of the most promising companies which provides an online B2B and B2C marketplace for the Diamond and Jewellery Industry. I was hired for one of their projects as a web developer. The project was about the automation and digitalization of the whole company's procedure for diamonds. I have worked on all the modules and was one of the core members of the team. While working there, I got proper exposure to working remotely and professionalism. It also helped me sharpen my PHP skills.

#### **EDUCATION**

2014

# **10**<sup>TH</sup> **STANDARD**, SHRI RAMKRISHNA HARIKRISHNA ACADEMY

I have completed my 10<sup>th</sup> standard from the Central Board of Secondary Education and got a **7.8/10 CGPA**. The most noticeable outcome was that my communication skills were improved as I was actively participating in presentations and group discussions.

2016

# **12**<sup>TH</sup> **STANDARD,** SHRI RAMKRISHNA HARIKRISHNA ACADEMY

My 12<sup>th</sup> standard was also from the Central Board of Secondary Education and got a **72.8/100 percentage**. I have learned many leadership and personal skills during the year. My journey to becoming a Computer Engineer begins here.

2020

#### **B.E. COMPUTER ENGINEERING, GUJARAT TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY**

I have passed my bachelor's from Bhagwan Mahavir College of Engineering and Technology; a Gujarat Technological University affiliated College with an **8.14/10 CGPA**. These four years made me an engineer and gave me the confidence to take over the world.

### **PROJECTS**

## • **ECOTRACK**, 2017-2019

The project was performed under the Design Engineering subject for two years. The Goal of Design Engineering was to identify real-life problems and give solutions concerning the resolution or elimination of the issue. The idea was to make bicycles a mode of transportation and a piece of equipment for fitness maintenance. The citizens are provided bicycles for rent in the city. Anyone can use these bicycles for their particular purpose with proper authentication. We used Technologies like JAVA NETBEANS for making the desktop application for allocating and deallocating the bikes and handling records and MYSQL for Backend database support. I took tasks like Database Connectivity and Interface design with a contribution to the System's programming. The project was significant to me as it was the first project under my leadership.

# GO DRIVE, 2019-2020

It was the final year project and was Industry Defined Project (IDP). We completed it with our Internship at a reputed software solutions company KNOXPO Solutions Pvt. Ltd. We did a project based on Angular, Firebase, and Android Studio. The project was to establish a digital platform between the motor driving school and its customers. The purpose of "GO DRIVE" is to fulfill the missing digital platform for driving schools. It allows the person who wants to learn driving can search for the preferred driving school and preferred time slot and then learn to drive. The other functionalities provided by "GO DRIVE" help the driving school manage the trainers, customers, access previous records of trainers and customers. It also gives analytics to the school in a graphical view. Angular was used for web application development as we were trying to make a single page web application with ease in code management. We also used Bootstrap, which makes web applications attractive, responsive, and dynamic. Firebase supported the backend, and for the mobile application, we used Android Studio. The project

was also under my leadership. I took responsibility for the Web application and Firebase Integration. We also learned about version controlling with GITHUB.

## • WEB APPLICATION FOR DIAMOND INDUSTRY, 2021

I was hired as an intern at Tradinget. It is one of the most promising companies which provides an online B2B and B2C marketplace for the Diamond and Jewellery Industry. The project was about the automation and digitalization of the whole company's procedure for diamonds. The app was made with PHP and MySQL. I have worked on both Frontend and Backend. I have contributed to all the modules, but most of my contribution was in Accounting, Backup, and Report module. For the first time, I worked under someone's leadership, and this experience was a must for me as I got an understanding of how to work under pressure under someone's supervision. It was a great experience, and the project was very informative as well.

## SKILLS

- Fluent in English, Hindi, and Gujarati
- Spanish (Beginner)
- Leadership
- Communication
- Teamwork
- Content Writing

- C Language, C++, Java, Python, MYSQL
- Web Development and Design
- Database Management Systems
- Github
- MS Office
- Creative Writing

## **ACTIVITIES**

- Participated in Leadership Training Camp in 2014. The Camp was for two days and was quite an event from a leader's perspective.
- Participated in events like Sherlock, Robo-Race, Relay-Coding in College's Tech-Fest and won 2<sup>nd</sup>
  Rank in Technical Quiz Event.
- Attended various workshops in College, which are Fundamentals of GIS GPS and GNSS, Entrepreneurship Awareness Camp, Seminar on topic .Net, Webinar on Python with Django.
- Completed Bridge Course Activity in College.
- Completed the test on **JAVA**, **LINUX**, and **PHP AND MYSQL** offered by the spoken tutorial project, IIT BOMBAY, funded by NATIONAL MISSION ON EDUCATION THROUGH ICT, MHRD, GOVT. OF INDIA.
- Completed **100 Points Activity**, the unique mechanism created by GTU to prepare its students to match diverse requirements from the industries.

# **EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

- Participated in National Science Olympiad in 2011 and 2012 and was first in school for the year 2011.
- Participated and Secured 3<sup>rd</sup> position in Inter-house Sports Competition 2014-2015 in football.
- Represented school In CBSE Football Cluster for three straight years 2014, 2015, and 2016.
- **Volunteered** for the Registration team of College's Tech-fest AAYAM-17.

- Participated in College's Cultural Festival's Football Competition in 2017, 2018, and 2019 and were Runners-up in 2018.
- Founding Member of College's Hobby club named Khwahish.
- I have won the Lan Gaming (Counterstrike) event in College's Cultural Fest for years 2017, 2018, and 2019.
- I, with my friend, brought a sponsorship of 18,000 INR for the Cultural Festival SPANDAN 2018.
- I have **organized** Lan Gaming Events (Counterstrike, Need for Speed, and PUBG mobile) for Cultural Festival SPANDAN 2020.

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Successfully completed **AI For Everyone**, an online course authorized by deeplearning.ai offered through Coursera.
- Successfully completed **Python Basics**, an online course approved by the University Of Michigan offered through Coursera.
- Completed **Front-End Web UI Frameworks and Tools: Bootstrap 4**, an online course offered by Coursera under the authorization of The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology.

# **BLOG**

• <a href="https://sahilahir.com/">https://sahilahir.com/</a>

# WEB PORTFOLIO

https://sahil-portfolio-cbc6e.web.app/home